Josh Marquardt

marquardt1195@gmail.com

(262) 455-1195

LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer with experience working on large-scale software solutions from conception to completion. Worked directly with company executives in a fast-paced technology startup with a demonstrated ability to communicate complex ideas simply and effectively.

SKILLS

- C#
- ASP.NET
- SQL (SQL Server, MySQL)
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- R
- Git
- Data analysis & visualization
- CI/CD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

January 2024 - Present

Low Cost Pet Tech, Co.

- Created a company-wide inventory management system from the ground up, improving efficiency and accuracy in inventory tracking.
- Built various RESTful API's to (1) merge existing databases with current data architecture, (2) improve performance by offloading tasks like sending reminder text messages and emails to customers.
- Developed software to interact with third-party API's including American Kennel Club and Homebase Employee Scheduling.
- Improve software performance by using various forms of data including XML & JSON.
- Assist in communicating key technical concepts and plans to company executives.

Software Development Intern

September 2023 – January 2024

Low Cost Pet Tech, Co.

Assist in the development of web applications using C# with ASP.NET, SQL Server, JS, HTML, and CSS.

Business Owner

January 2021 – July 2023

SLC Vintage Goods LLC

- Co-founded online vintage furniture company with avg. of 93% YoY revenue growth since inception.
- Used HTML and CSS to develop company website: slcvintagegoods.github.io

Graduate Research Fellow

August 2018 - December 2020

University of Utah & Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory

- Used R to process and visualize data to conduct original research in geophysics. Published sample:
 Figure 3 in https://sd.copernicus.org/articles/25/35/2019/
- Used R to analyze, process, and visualize data from various laboratory instruments, streamlining laboratory procedures for all users.

EDUCATION

University of Utah - M.S., Geophysics

August 2018 – December 2020

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee – B.S., Geosciences

January 2014 - May 2018